After the Quake
by Haruki Murakami
Read by Rupert Degas, Teresa Gallagher, and Adam Sims
UNABRIDGED

4 CDs 
Running Time: 4:19:02 
Sample Rate : 44100 Hz
Channels : 2
Avg. Bitrate : 67 kbps
Codec : MP3
Codec Profile : MP3 VBR V5
Tool : LAME3.97


In 1995, the Japanese city of Kobe suffered a massive earthquake. Nearly 6,000 people died. after the quake was the imaginative response from Japan’s leading novelist, Haruki Murakami: six stories, each dealing not directly with the catastrophe but the wider seismic effect it had on the emotional lives of people many miles away.

It became a catalyst for individuals to reassess their lives with unexpected consequences for themselves and their families and friends around them. after the quake is Murakami’s most popular short story collection.

  
Amazon.com Reviews:

All of Murakami's novels are best sellers, and he is perhaps the most recognized and noted Japanese author in the U.S. and around the world. Murakami is one of my favorite authors. I have enjoyed all of his previous novels, and now this little book of short stories kept me turning the pages past the midnight hour. Murakami drew me in with his simple language and the powerful dialogue of his intriguing characters. These six stories are all related to the devastating Kobe earthquake of 1995. The stories are set in the months between the natural disaster and the poison gas attacks that occurred in Tokyo's subways. Both of these events dramatically changed the physical and social landscape of Japan. For each of the characters in these stories, the earthquake's emotional aftershock set off an unreal chain of events.
I enjoyed all of these stories, but a few were my favorites. In "Super-Frog Saves Tokyo", a loan-collector teams up with a man-sized frog to fight an enormous worm that threatens to destroy Tokyo. In "Landscape With Flatiron", we learn about Miyake's passion in building bonfires with his companion Junko, and what it all symbolizes. And last but not least, in "Honey Pie", we are presented with a complex, passionate story about a love triangle that takes place over many years. 


We are exposed to a lot of human suffering in these stories. Murakami, however, sheds light and hope in all of these stories by showing us the courage, strength, and compassion these devastated people possess in overcoming any tragedy that they may have to face. I always look forward to Murakami's new novels. Now, I can, hopefully, look forward to more short stories by this talented author. This is a beautifully written collection of stories. Hope you enjoy it as much as I did! 

Joe Hanssen

-------------------------

At the end of my first semester as a graduate student I was faced with the task of writing two fifteen to twenty page papers on the works of Ihara Saikaku. Having already finished reading Five Women who Loved Love and The Life of an Amorous Man, I was then faced with the task of reading his longest work The Great Mirror of Male Love which, after a long and dense introduction by the translator goes into minute detail about the male loves of the samurai and kabuki actors. Faced with the task of reading all forty short stories contained in the book, I turned to Murakami Haruki's after the quake to give my mind a break from the massive tome of Edo period homo-erotica. Since that time after the quake has been a story collection that I have turned to a number of times when I needed something quick and enjoyable to read when faced with a large number of books for graduate school. This, of course, does not mean that after the quake is fluff reading, because that is far from the case. The time period this collection of short stories takes place is during February 1995, the month sandwiched between the Kobe Earthquake which occurred on January 17th and the Aum Shinrikyo's sarin gas attacks that occurred on March 20th of the same year. Although none of the six short stories' protagonists were directly harmed by the earthquake, each one is affected by its "aftershocks." 

UFO in Kushiro: the collection opens with the story of Komura a handsome, successful sales representative whose wife leaves him after the Kobe Earthquake. Leaving a note that states that living with Komura is like living with a "chunk of air" Komura's wife heads back north to her home and sends her husband the divorce papers. Needing a break from work in order to think, Komura goes to Hokkaido to deliver a package for a coworker and there he meets two young women who try to put his life into perspective. 

Landscape with Flatiron: This short story tells the tale of Junko a young woman who ran away to Ibaraki to escape the stifling atmosphere of her home and school. Seemingly content with her surfer boyfriend Keisuke, Junko also enjoys the company of Miyake a small, balding man who likes to make bonfires on the beach. This short story describes what may be the final meeting between Junko and Miyake. In my opinion, this might be the saddest story within the book. 

All God's Children can Dance: Yoshiya seems like a decent enough fellow. He might enjoy drinking too much, but he gets along with his coworkers and he has a string of girlfriends who like the way he dances. He is also the son of God. Or at least this is what he is told by his mother who was "saved" by a member of new religion group when she was going to commit suicide after becoming pregnant with Yoshiya after following her doctor/lover's contraceptive methods perfectly. Not believing that he is the son of God, Yoshiya eventually spots a man who looks like an older version of the man his mother slept with almost three decades before. One day pursues this man and he finds... 

Thailand: After going to a large gathering of thyroid specialists, Satsuki decides to spend some of her vacation time in Thailand. In the capable hands of her chauffeur Nimit, Satsuki is able to relax, swim, and enjoy impeccable little cucumber and cheese sandwiches. However, anger burns within her. With her ex-husband living in Kobe, Satsuki hopes that the bane of her life has been crushed the fallen debris. However, to be truly whole again, she must release he anger. 

Super Frog Saves Tokyo: Katagiri is an average fellow, perhaps even below average. Short, bald, and basically unlikable, the only thing that he is successful at is his job collecting overdue loans. However, one day, something spectacular happens to Katagiri. After arriving home from the grocery store, Katagiri encounters a six-foot tall frog in his kitchen. Able to quote Nabokov, Tolstoy, and Dostoyevsky, Frog informs Katagiri that he needs his help in the battle with Worm, a huge blind worm that was awakened by the earthquake in Kobe and is determined to cause an enormous earthquake that will destroy Tokyo and only Katagiri can help him prevent it! 

Honey Pie: Probably the sappiest short story that Murakami has ever penned, however, it is also quite effective in tugging on the heart strings. A trio in college: Junpei, Sayoko, and Takatsuki spent all of there time with each other eating out, going to movies, drinking beer, and sharing notes. Brought together by the outgoing Takatsuki, Sayoko and Junpei generally went along with what Takatsuki wanted to do. Also, although Junpei loved Sayoko, and it seemed Sayoko loved him as well, he was afraid to express his feelings, and Takatsuki beat him to the punch and asked Sayoko to marry him. Although his world almost crumbled around hi, Junpei endured to become a moderately successful short story writer. Now Sayoko and Takatsuki are divorced and Sayoko lives alone with her daughter Sala. Can Junpei finally tell the woman he loves his true feelings? 

While the earthquake itself is rarely addressed directly, it plays a role in that it gives a jolt to each of the protagonists' lives and changes them for better or worse. Murakami, a loner himself, can perfectly paint the portrait of loneliness and it is this skill that makes these stories so effective and while it May not be one of Murakami's best works, after the quake is still a good, quick read and it might be a good starting point for the Murakami novice. 

Michael W.

-------------------------

Other review:

The English title of this collection, After the Quake, refers to the devastating earthquake that hit Japan in 1995, centered around Kobe in the Kansai region. It is not one of the story titles, but rather a summing-up overview. (The Japanese title is the same as one of the stories, "All God's Children can Dance".) 

The earthquake is a presence in each of the stories, an event that is mentioned and that has had some sort of lingering (though usually only tangential) effect on at least some of the characters. Murakami never really ventures to earthquake-country, or describes what the effects were there: he is more interested in the larger effects, on the country as a whole and those peripherally affected. The earthquake is merely another symptom of the general unease and uncertainty faced by contemporary Japan. 

There are six stories in this small collection. Most of it is the usual Murakami-stuff: lost souls, odd encounters, late nights, unlikely and inexplicable creatures and occurrences, some jazz music, some unfulfilled love, disappearances, and at least one Murakami-like author. The book is sparsely populated: characters often meet late at night or in isolation. There are few crowds, and people have few friends. 

Particularly striking is the trust found in the novel, with strangers forming unlikely bonds. Friendships also are reliable, the rare bond (unlike marriage or family relationships) that holds. But even where there are divorces these are not rancorous. Murakami's interpersonal relationships are pleasant but so unlike most people's experience that they help give the collection a very surreal feel. 

In "UFO in Kushiro" the central character's wife leaves him, a sudden and complete break -- without, of course, any personal confrontation: he just returns home to find she has gone. The man, Komura, then travels to Hokkaido at the suggestion of a colleague, who has him deliver a mysterious small box. The Kobe earthquake plays a large role here, both in his wife's leaving and as a reflection of his own unsettled state. 

"Landscape with Flatiron" is dominated by a late-night beachside bonfire lighting. Not much happens, the most tense moments involving the question of whether the collected driftwood will catch fire. Yet it still manages to be a nice reflection of youthful life and concerns: 

What's important is now. Who knows when the world is gonna end ? Who can think about the future ? 

In "All God's Children can Dance" Yoshiya is the son of a woman who found religion (and is, during the story, down in Kansai helping with the earthquake relief). He only learnt the 'secret' of his mysterious birth when he was seventeen. Here he believes to see the man who might be his father. He follows him, and finds release from some of what oppressed him. The story verges on the mystical. 

"Thailand" represents a rare foreign foray for Murakami. After attending a conference, Satsuki takes a vacation at a resort. Her driver, Nimit, is the perfect care-taker for her, taking her to a secluded swimming pool away from the hotel where she can rest and swim in peace. Nimit is also an unusual man, having worked for thirty years for a Norwegian who fled to Thailand. The two form an odd bond, and help each other in a way. Again, the story moves towards the mystical. 

"Super-Frog saves Tokyo" tells of an odd relationship between Katagiri and a frog that appears to him and asks him to help save Tokyo from an earthquake far more devastating than the one in Kansai. What sounds ridiculous at first unfolds in neat turns into a surprisingly appealing tale, each advance never quite the expected one. Note also that the frog is just called "Frog" or "Mr.Frog" in the story itself; the name "Super-Frog" is from another story, "All God's Children can Dance": it is what Yoshiya's girlfriend called him in college ..... 
       Frog -- who spouts Nietzsche and reads the Russian greats -- tells Katagiri: 
The whole terrible fight occurred in the area of imagination. That is the precise location of our battlefield. It is there that we experience our victories and our defeats. 
So it is often in Murakami's work, but here far more explicitly than usual. 

The final story, "Honey Pie", presents a familiar wistful Murakami-scenario: an odd threesome (two men who love one woman), a small child (to whom stories are told), and a somewhat successful writer. The writer is looking to the new -- in his personal life, in what he wants to write. He takes a first stab at action, but it's never that easy. Here an 'Earthquake Man' interferes ..... But there is hope at the end. 

A nice collection, more resonant than it might first appear. Deceptively simple, with the familiar Murakami tropes, there is more to these stories than first meets the eye.

-----------------------

7 mp3 files
==================================================================================
   
   101 _ UFO in Kushiro.mp3                                                                            
   107 _ Landscape with Flatiron.mp3                                                                   
   201 _ All God's Children Can Dance.mp3                                                              
   208 _ Thailand.mp3                                                                                  
   304 _ Superfrog Saves Tokyo.mp3                                                                     
   401 _ Honey Pie _ Part One.mp3                                                                      
   407 _ Honey Pie _ Part Two.mp3                                                                      
                                                                                
==================================================================================